A Guide to the Virginia Committee on Opportunities in Virginia Agriculture, Records, 1964-1969
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records, 1964-1969
Library of Virginia
40567
1 cubic foot
Virginia Committee on Opportunities in Virginia Agriculture
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
No acquisition information available.
Historical Information
The General Assembly of Virginia created the Commission of the Industry of Agriculture in 1962 to advise the Governor on the state of agriculture in Virginia and on a course of action to promote its development, to encourage and counsel persons, agencies, organizations and industries in implementing a development program. The Commission was also to work closely with agencies concerned with industrial development, coordinating efforts toward maximum farm and off-farm employment; to examine marketing procedures and new techniques for selling Virginia's farm products; and to devise plans for developing new markets for such products.
In 1966 Governor Mills E. Godwin, Jr., requested the Commission of the Industry of Agriculture to conduct ad comprehensive study to determine "what the future holds for Virginia agriculture." The Commission subsequently created the Committee on Opportunities in Virginia Agriculture with the objectives of (1) evaluating the present position and future potential of agriculture in Virginia; (2) defining agriculture in relation to other facets of the economy; (3) identifying adjustment opportunities in agriculture; and (4) pointing out means for more efficient resource use (land, labor, water, and capital).
Eight task force groups were established to achieve these objectives: Dairy, Livestock, Poultry, Horses, Agronomic Crops, Horticulture Crops, Forest Products, and General Resources. The membership consisted of key leaders representing all facets of the industry of agriculture and the task forces conducted two years of intensive research, which concluded in a final report to the Governor in 1969.
Scope and Content Information
The records in this collection were assembled by T. Edward Temple, who served as the chairman of the General Resources Task Force, which was one of the task forces of the Committee on Opportunities in Virginia Agriculture. Mr. Temple was also the Director of the Division of Planning and Community Affairs. The General Resources Task Force was sub-divided into six study groups: Capital and Credit Study Committee; Education Study Committee; Land Assessment Study Committee; Public Services Study Committee; Soil Resources Study Committee; and Water in Agriculture Study Committee. The majority of the records relate to the study committees of the General Resources Task Force, but the collection also includes general records from several of the other task forces. Records include correspondence, minutes, reports, statistical compilations and publications.
Contents List
- General Resources Task Force - Correspondence, 1968 Feb-Sep (Box 1, Folder 1)
- General Resources Task Force - Correspondence, 1968 Oct-Nov (Box 1, Folder 2)
- General Resources Task Force - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- General Resources Task Force - Capital and Credit Study Committee, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- General Resources Task Force - Capital and Credit Study Committee, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- General Resources Task Force - Education Study Committee, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- General Resources Task Force - Education Study Committee, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- General Resources Task Force - Land Assessment Study Committee, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- General Resources Task Force - Public Services, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- General Resources Task Force - Water in Agriculture Study Committee, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- General Resources Task Force - Water in Agriculture Study Committee, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- General Resources Task Force - Miscellaneous publications, 1964-1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Argonomic Task Force - Report, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Forest Products Task Force - Report, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Horse Industry Task Force - Study, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Consolidated State Report (preliminary draft), 1969 (Box 1, Folder 16)